historyextra.com 2013-03-26

# Privacy Policy | Immediate Media Co.

**1\. INTRODUCTION AND GENERAL TERMS**

Immediate Media Company Limited (‘Immediate’) is committed to protecting your personal information when you are using Immediate services. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for you to use. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us.

In order to provide you with the full range of Immediate services, we are sometimes required to collect information about you.

This privacy policy explains the following:

  * what information Immediate may collect about you;
  * how Immediate will use information we collect about you;
  * whether Immediate will disclose your details to anyone else;
  * when Immediate may use your details to contact you;
  * your choices regarding the personal information you have provided to us.

As set out above, Immediate is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information, including the Data Protection Act 1998 (these laws are referred to collectively in this Privacy Policy as the “data protection laws”).

Our websites may contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, including cookies, and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information which you submit or which is collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

**2\. WHAT INFORMATION WILL IMMEDIATE COLLECT ABOUT ME?**

When you sign up to participate in or receive a service from Immediate, such as newsletters, competitions, magazine subscriptions, ordering products, readers’ offers, live chats, message boards, surveys or online registration we may ask for personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth. Different services or webpages may ask for different personal information.

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable Immediate and its service providers to provide you with the services you select.

Please note that sometimes on particular services (e.g. chat forums) you may be asked to provide or you may volunteer additional personal information and sometimes sensitive personal information (e.g. your political opinions, religious beliefs, sex life or health).

We may also use your IP address for some of our website services (see **section 3: How will Immediate use the information they collect about me?** and our **Cookies Policy** for more information;).

  **3\. HOW WILL IMMEDIATE USE THE INFORMATION THEY COLLECT ABOUT ME?**

Immediate will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following:

  * for service administration purposes, which means that Immediate may contact you for reasons related to the service you have signed up for, as set out in **section 5: When will Immediate contact me?** below (e.g. to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service has been suspended for maintenance);
  * to notify you of changes to our service;
  * to contact you about a submission you have made to our websites or magazines, including any content you provide (follow the link to our Code of Conduct at the bottom of the main pages of our websites for more details about making online submissions);
  * to personalise or improve the way Immediate content and advertising is presented to you online:
  * Immediate may collect your IP address (an IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet) and place cookies (please see our **Cookies Policy** for more information); for the purpose of improving our sites and enhancing your user experience, sometimes including the display of selected ads which are appropriate to your browsing pattern. This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you;
  * IP addresses may also be used to identify the location of users, the number of visits from different countries and also to block disruptive use;
  * to analyse and improve the services offered by a Immediate website, e.g. to provide you with the most user-friendly navigation experience (please see our **Cookies Policy** for more information);
  * to manage our competitions and contact the winners;
  * to meet product orders or requests for services or information; to process payments; and to keep our records up to date;
  * where you have specifically consented to be contacted for these purposes, to send you direct marketing by telephone, post or email about special offers and current or new products that you may be interested in;
  * to enable other people or businesses to carry out work on our behalf; and
  * where you have given us your permission, to pass your information to carefully selected organisations to allow them to tell you about their special offers or products and services that may be of interest to you.
  * Where Immediate proposes using your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for your use other than as listed above.

**4\. WILL IMMEDIATE SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH ANYONE ELSE?**

Generally, we will only use your information within the Immediate Media Company group of companies in order to provide the service/product you have requested.

We will only disclose your data to third party data processors with your consent or where we need to do so in order to provide a service. The data processors to whom we may pass your data will be Immediate Media Company group companies and appropriately contracted third parties. Otherwise, we will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or as described in **section 7: Offensive or inappropriate content on Immediate’s websites** below.

Immediate will require all third party data processors to whom your information is disclosed to comply strictly with its instructions and Immediate will require that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes.

Where we share your information with third party companies which are situated outside the EEA we will ensure they treat your information with the same protection we do.

**5\. WHEN WILL IMMEDIATE CONTACT ME?**

Immediate may contact you:

  * in relation to the functioning of any service you have signed up for in order to ensure that Immediate can deliver the services to you;
  * in relation to any contribution you have made to any Immediate website, message board or other service;
  * where you have opted to receive newsletters or other correspondence;
  * to invite you to participate in surveys about Immediate services (participation is always voluntary);
  * to carry out obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and Immediate; and
  * for marketing purposes where you have specifically agreed to this (see **section 6: Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?** below).

Our magazines or websites will give you detailed information about how Immediate will contact you in relation to specific services.

**6\. WILL I BE CONTACTED FOR MARKETING PURPOSES?**

Immediate won’t contact you for marketing purposes, or promote new services to you unless you agree to be contacted for these purposes.

**7\. OFFENSIVE OR INAPPROPRIATE CONTENT ON IMMEDIATE’S WEBSITES**

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on a Immediate website, or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour, Immediate may use your personal information to stop such behaviour.

Where Immediate reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of the law (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory), Immediate may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your employer, school e-mail/Internet provider or law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.

**8\. WHAT IF I AM A USER AGED 16 OR UNDER?**

If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide personal information to Immediate. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

**9\. HOW LONG WILL IMMEDIATE KEEP MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant service, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with Immediate or Immediate’s corporate retention schedule. If you wish to cancel your registration with any of Immediate’s websites, you may do so by following the “unsubscribe” instructions on the relevant website. If you change your profile to opt-out of receiving communications, your record may stay on the system so we can ensure that we do not contact you in the future.

Where you contribute to a Immediate service or website, Immediate will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted.

**10\. CAN I FIND OUT WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION IMMEDIATE HOLDS ABOUT ME?**

Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the personal information Immediate holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. (We charge £10 for information requests and will require you to prove your identity with 2 pieces of approved photographic identification.) We will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files.

If you have any requests or questions about this or any other question about this Privacy Policy please see **section 13: Contacting Immediate about this Privacy Policy** at the bottom of this document.

**11\. CHANGES TO IMMEDIATE’S PRIVACY POLICY**

This privacy policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to any Immediate service. The date of the most recent revisions will appear at the bottom of this page.

**12\. CONTACTING IMMEDIATE ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact:

The Company Secretary, Vineyard House, 44 Brook Green, Hammersmith, London, W6 7BT, United Kingdom

Tel: +44(0)20 7150 5000

Email: [dataprotection@immediate.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@immediate.co.uk)

**Last updated: May 2012**
